# **Swapnil Rawat**

Pune, Maharashtra, India



rawatswapnil911@gmail.com



7397437569



linkedin.com/in/swapnil-rawat-866475147

# **Summary**

I am a Certified Salesforce developer, with a passion for all things Salesforce. With some experience in development and management of complex business processes and systems. I am specialized in apex programming, new process design/implementation and integration procedures. I am also proficient in the use of tools and methods such as apex triggers, process builder, lightning web components, data loader, API integration, vlocity document templates, dataraptors and lightning app builder.

# **Experience**

#### **Associate Salesforce Developer**

Bajaj Finserv Health

Jul 2021 - Present (7 months +)

- Implementation of Platform events to overcome async operation limits
- Designed and implemented Event based data sync for Salesforce-Mobile app integration using Cometd with Kafka
- · Creating and managing custom objects, fields, and page layouts
- Creating and managing custom processes, apex triggers, integration procedures, and document templates
- Implemented several other projects including the two above
- · Heavy data management focus with mass updates using data loader

# Technology Intern

Bajaj Finserv Health Feb 2021 - Jun 2021 (5 months)



#### **Android Development Intern**

**ATechnos** 

May 2020 - Jun 2020 (2 months)

#### Frontend Development Intern

CogniAble

May 2019 - May 2019 (1 month)



#### **Marketing Team**

Renaissance VITC Sep 2018 - Jan 2019 (5 months)

### **Education**



## Vellore Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Science 2017 - 2021

#### FARIDABAD CONVENT SCHOOL - India

12th, PCM 2015 - 2016



#### 🌉 Kendriya vidyalaya

10th 2013 - 2014

#### **Licenses & Certifications**



Programming , Data Structures And Algorithms Using Python - NPTEL



Vlocity Platform Essentials (VPE) - Vlocity



Salesforce Certified Platform Developer I - Salesforce

22711155

#### **Skills**

Salesforce.com Development • Salesforce Vlocity • Apex Programming • Front-end Development • Android Development • Salesforce.com • Salesforce Lightning • Salesforce Sales Cloud • Salesforce Service Cloud • Lightning Web Components

#### **Honors & Awards**



Hero of the Moment - September 2021 - Bajaj Finserv Health

Nov 2021

Award for exploring the platform events options and executing on the POC